

{
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "Which of the following statements describe the features of dynamic code analysis? (Select 3 answers)",
      "options": [
        "Typically used later in the software development lifecycle",
        "Involves examining the code without executing it",
        "Analyzes runtime properties like memory usage, performance, and error handling to identify issues such as memory leaks, performance bottlenecks, and runtime errors",
        "Often used early in the development process",
        "Examines code structure, syntax, and semantics to detect issues like syntax errors, coding standards violations, security vulnerabilities, and bugs",
        "Involves executing the code and analyzing its behavior at runtime"
      ],
      "correct_answers": [
        "Typically used later in the software development lifecycle",
        "Analyzes runtime properties like memory usage, performance, and error handling to identify issues such as memory leaks, performance bottlenecks, and runtime errors",
        "Involves executing the code and analyzing its behavior at runtime"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the terms listed below refers to tracking and managing software application components, such as third-party libraries and other dependencies?",
      "options": [
        "Version control",
        "Package monitoring",
        "Configuration enforcement",
        "Application hardening"
      ],
      "correct_answers": ["Package monitoring"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following terms refers to threat intelligence gathered from publicly available sources?",
      "options": ["IoC", "OSINT", "RFC", "CVE/NVD"],
      "correct_answers": ["OSINT"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the terms listed below refers to a US government initiative for real-time sharing of cyber threat indicators?",
      "options": ["AIS", "STIX", "TTP", "CVSS"],
      "correct_answers": ["AIS"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is STIX?",
      "options": [
        "A type of vulnerability database",
        "Common language for describing cyber threat information",
        "US government initiative for real-time sharing of cyber threat indicators",
        "Transport mechanism for cyber threat information"
      ],
      "correct_answers": ["Common language for describing cyber threat information"]
    },
    {
      "question": "A dedicated transport mechanism for cyber threat information is called:",
      "options": ["TCP/IP", "TLS", "TAXII", "S/MIME"],
      "correct_answers": ["TAXII"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following provides insights into the methods and tools used by cybercriminals to carry out attacks?",
      "options": ["CVE", "IoC", "AIS", "TTP"],
      "correct_answers": ["TTP"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following statements does not apply to dark web?",
      "options": [
        "Typically requires specialized software to access its contents",
        "Forms a large part of the deep web",
        "Not indexed by traditional search engines",
        "Often associated with trading stolen data, malware, and cyber threats"
      ],
      "correct_answers": ["Forms a large part of the deep web"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Penetration testing: (Select all that apply)",
      "options": [
        "Bypasses security controls",
        "Only identifies lack of security controls",
        "Actively tests security controls",
        "Exploits vulnerabilities",
        "Passively tests security controls"
      ],
      "correct_answers": [
        "Bypasses security controls",
        "Actively tests security controls",
        "Exploits vulnerabilities"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "A responsible disclosure program is a formal process established by an organization to encourage security researchers and ethical hackers to report vulnerabilities they discover in the organization's systems or software. A bug bounty program is a specific type of responsible disclosure program that offers financial rewards to security researchers for reporting valid vulnerabilities.",
      "options": ["True", "False"],
      "correct_answers": ["True"]
    },
    {
      "question": "An antivirus software identifying a non-malicious file as a virus due to a faulty virus signature file is an example of:",
      "options": ["Fault tolerance", "False positive error", "Quarantine feature", "False negative error"],
      "correct_answers": ["False positive error"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the answers listed below refers to a situation where no alarm is raised when an attack has taken place?",
      "options": ["False negative", "True positive", "False positive", "True negative"],
      "correct_answers": ["False negative"]
    },
    {
      "question": "A measure of the likelihood that a security system will incorrectly reject an access attempt by an authorized user is referred to as:",
      "options": ["FAR", "CER", "CRC", "FRR"],
      "correct_answers": ["FRR"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following terms refers to a framework and knowledge base that provides understanding of TTPs used during cyberattacks?",
      "options": ["CVSS", "ATT&CK", "STIX", "TAXII"],
      "correct_answers": ["ATT&CK"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the answers listed below refers to an industry standard for assessing and scoring the severity of computer system security vulnerabilities?",
      "options": ["SIEM", "CVSS", "OSINT", "SOAR"],
      "correct_answers": ["CVSS"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following refers to a system that identifies, defines, and catalogs publicly known cybersecurity vulnerabilities?",
      "options": ["TAXII", "CVE", "STIX", "CVSS"],
      "correct_answers": ["CVE"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is Exposure Factor (EF) in vulnerability analysis?",
      "options": [
        "The likelihood that a vulnerability will be exploited in a real-world scenario",
        "The rate at which vulnerabilities are discovered and reported",
        "The degree of loss that a realized threat would have on a specific asset",
        "The measure of the potential impact of a vulnerability on an organization's assets"
      ],
      "correct_answers": ["The degree of loss that a realized threat would have on a specific asset"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the statements listed below does not refer to a vulnerability response and remediation technique?",
      "options": [
        "Applying updates or fixes provided by software vendors to address the vulnerability (patching)",
        "Ensuring financial recovery from the costs associated with a successful cyberattack (insurance)",
        "Dividing a network into smaller, isolated zones to limit the potential impact of a vulnerability (segmentation)",
        "Mitigating the risk associated with a vulnerability that cannot be immediately patched by implementing alternative security measures (compensating controls)",
        "Delaying or forgoing a patch for a specific system, e.g., when applying a patch may not be feasible due to compatibility issues or potential disruptions to critical systems (exceptions and exemptions)",
        "All of the above answers are examples of vulnerability response and remediation techniques"
      ],
      "correct_answers": ["All of the above answers are examples of vulnerability response and remediation techniques"]
    },
    {
      "question": "The practice of isolating potentially malicious or suspicious entities to prevent them from causing harm to the rest of the network or system is known as:",
      "options": ["Sandboxing", "Containerization", "Quarantine", "Segmentation"],
      "correct_answers": ["Quarantine"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the answers listed below refer to SCAP? (Select 3 answers)",
      "options": [
        "A type of security system designed to collect logs and events from various sources",
        "Designed to provide a centralized user interface for accessing collected data",
        "A collection of standards developed by NIST",
        "Provides a common language for communicating security information",
        "Allows different security tools to share data and work together more effectively",
        "Enables real-time threat detection, incident response, and compliance monitoring"
      ],
      "correct_answers": [
        "A collection of standards developed by NIST",
        "Provides a common language for communicating security information",
        "Allows different security tools to share data and work together more effectively"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the answers listed below refer to SIEM? (Select 3 answers)",
      "options": [
        "Allows different security tools to share data and work together more effectively",
        "Designed to provide a centralized user interface for accessing collected data",
        "A collection of standards developed by NIST",
        "Enables real-time threat detection, incident response, and compliance monitoring",
        "A type of security system designed to collect logs and events from various sources",
        "Provides a common language for communicating security information"
      ],
      "correct_answers": [
        "Designed to provide a centralized user interface for accessing collected data",
        "Enables real-time threat detection, incident response, and compliance monitoring",
        "A type of security system designed to collect logs and events from various sources"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following acronyms refers to software or hardware-based security solutions designed to detect and prevent unauthorized use and transmission of confidential information?",
      "options": ["IPS", "DLP", "IDS", "DEP"],
      "correct_answers": ["DLP"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Simple Network Management Protocol (SNMP) is a UDP-based, application layer protocol used in network management systems to monitor network-attached devices... The manager receives notifications (Traps and InformRequests) on UDP port 162, while the SNMP Agent receives requests on UDP port 161.",
      "options": ["True", "False"],
      "correct_answers": ["True"]
    },
    {
      "question": "An SNMP-compliant device includes a virtual database containing information about configuration and state of the device that can be queried by an SNMP management station. This type of data repository is referred to as:",
      "options": ["MIB", "DCS", "NMS", "SIEM"],
      "correct_answers": ["MIB"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Of the three existing versions of the Simple Network Management Protocol (SNMP), versions 1 and 2 (SNMPv1 and SNMPv2) offer authentication based on community strings sent in an unencrypted form (a.k.a. cleartext). SNMPv3 provides packet encryption, authentication, and hashing mechanisms that allow for checking whether data has changed in transit.",
      "options": ["True", "False"],
      "correct_answers": ["True"]
    }
  ]
}